Register of the William Patrick Clark papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Post-Government Service File, 1985-2008
  - Business records
    - Molana-Ireland (Irish company), 1998-1999 (Box-folder 163: 5-6, Box-folder 164: 1)
      Relates to investment in oil production in Iraq
    - Oppenheimer Industries, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 164: 2)
      Relates to dispute with U.S. Bureau of Reclamation over land use in New Mexico
    - P. W. Gillibrand Company, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 164: 3)
      Relates to dispute with U.S. Forestry Service over land use in California
    - Pacific Telesis Corporation, 1985 (Box-folder 164: 4)
    - PanLabs International, Inc. (pharmaceutical company), 1991-1995 (Box-folder 164: 5-7)
    - SBC Communications (Southwestern Bell Communications)
      - 1996-1998 (Box-folder 165: 1)
      - 2000 (Box-folder 165: 2)
      - 2001 (Box-folder 165: 3)
      - 2002 (Box-folder 165: 4-5)
      - 2003 (Box-folder 166: 1)
      - 2004 (Box-folder 166: 2-4)
      - 2005 (Box-folder 166: 5)
    - Saudi Fal Company (Saudi Arabian company), 1985-1991 (Box-folder 167: 1-2)
      See also Iraq/Aqaba Pipeline Project
    - Taiwan Trust, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 167: 3)
    - U.S. Asia Commercial Development Corporation
      Includes material on telecommunictions in Taiwan, Kyrgyzstan and Uzbeikistan
      - 2000 (Box-folder 167: 4)
      - 2001 (Box-folder 167: 5)
      - 2002 (Box-folder 167: 6)
      - 2003 (Box-folder 167: 7)
    - U.S. Three Gorges Working Group
      Relates to proposal by consortium of American companies for dam construction and hydroelectric power development on the Yangtze River in China
      - 1985 (Box-folder 168: 1-2, Box-folder 167: 8)
      - 1986 (Box-folder 168: 3)
    - U.S. Trading and Investment Company, 1990-1996 (Box-folder 168: 4)
      Includes material on investment in Taiwan and Mexico
    - United States Taiwan Transit Group, 1985 (Box-folder 168: 5)
      Includes material on transportation and nuclear power plants in Taiwan and South Korea
    - Unocal (Union Oil Company of California), 1985 (Box-folder 168: 6)
      Relates to litigation over corporate takeover attempt
    - Westinghouse Company
      Includes material on U.S.-Mexico border aerial surveillance system, also involving Northrop Grumman Company
      - 1992-1993 (Box-folder 169: 1)
      - 1994 (Box-folder 169: 2-3)
      - 1995 (Box-folder 169: 4-5)
      - 1996 (Box-folder 170: 1-2)
      - 1997 (Box-folder 170: 3)
      - 1998 (Box-folder 170: 4)
  - Subject file
    - Abbey of New Clairvaux (California), 2006 (Box-folder 170: 5)
    - Access Ministries, 1994-2002 (Box-folder 170: 6)
    - Aerial photography, 1991-2002 (Box-folder 170: 7)
    - American Bar Association Standing Committee on Law and National Security, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 170: 8)
    - Americans United for Life
      Correspondence and printed matter
      - 1995 (Box-folder 171: 1)
      - 1996 (Box-folder 171: 2)
      - 1997-2000 (Box-folder 171: 3)
    - Austria
      - Correspondence, 1990-2000 (Box-folder 171: 4)
      - Printed matter, 1985-2002 (Box-folder 171: 5)
    - Ave Maria School of Law (Ann Arbor, Michigan), 2005 (Box-folder 171: 6)
    - California Governor's Office
      - 1992-1995 (Box-folder 172: 1)
      - 1996-2000 (Box-folder 172: 2)
    - California Polytechnic State University (San Luis Obispo)
      - General, 1985-2002 (Box-folder 172: 3)
      - Performing Arts Center, 1988-1996 (Box-folder 172: 4)
      - President's Cabinet, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 172: 5)
        Meeting materials. Clark was a member of the Cabinet
    - California ProLife Council, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 172: 6)
      Correspondence and legal documents
    - Carrizo Plain National Monument (California), 2001 (Box-folder 172: 7)
      Correspondence and clipping
    - Catholic Radio Network
      Clark was a member of the Board
      - General
        - 1998 (Box-folder 173: 1-3)
        - 1999 (Box-folder 174: 1-2, Box-folder 173: 4)
        - 2000 (Box-folder 174: 3)
      - Information memorandum, 1999 (Box-folder 174: 4-5)
      - Meeting materials, 1998 (Box-folder 175: 1, Box-folder 174: 6)
      - Legal documents, 1998 (Box-folder 175: 2-4)
    - Center for Bio-Ethical Reform, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 175: 5)
    - Center for Strategic and International Studies, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 175: 6)
      Legal documents
    - Christian Legal Society, 1997 (Box-folder 176: 1)
    - Citizens for America, 1988 (Box-folder 176: 2)
      Letter
    - City of El Paso de Robles (California) Movie Theatre Project, 1996 (Box-folder 176: 3)
    - Commission on Integrated Long-Term Strategy, 1986 (Box-folder 176: 4)
      Letter and memoranda
    - Council for National Policy, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 176: 5)
    - Daughters of St. Paul, 1995-2002 (Box-folder 176: 6)
    - Deaver, Michael, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 176: 7)
      Clippings
    - Eyring Company, 1989 (Box-folder 176: 8)
    - Founding Fathers
      - General, 1988-1999 (Box-folder 176: 9)
        Correspondence, speeches and printed matter
      - Declaration of America, 1998 (Box-folder 176: 10)
        Draft curriculum document by Richard Ferrier and Andrew Seeley
    - Friends of Historic San Antonio Mission (Jolon, California), 1991-2000 (Box-folder 176: 11)
      Correspondence, memoranda and miscellany
    - Gherini Ranch
      Correspondence, memoranda, legal documents and printed matter relating to negotiations for U.S. National Park Service acquisition of property on Santa Cruz Island, California, owned by Francis Gherini for inclusion in Channel Islands National Park, and its eventual seizure. Clark acted as attorney for Gherini
      - 1988 (Box-folder 177: 1)
      - 1989 (Box-folder 177: 2)
      - 1990 (Box-folder 177: 3)
      - 1991 (Box-folder 177: 4)
      - 1992 (Box-folder 177: 5)
      - 1993 (Box-folder 177: 6)
      - 1994 (Box-folder 178: 1)
      - 1995 (Box-folder 178: 2)
      - 1996 (Box-folder 178: 3-4)
      - 1997 (Box-folder 178: 5)
      - 1998 (Box-folder 178: 6)
      - 1999 (Box-folder 179: 1)
      - 2000 (Box-folder 179: 2)
      - 2001 (Box-folder 179: 3)
      - 2003 (Box-folder 179: 4)
    - Heritage Foundation
      - 1985-1997 (Box-folder 179: 5)
      - 1998-2002 (Box-folder 180: 1)
    - Horses, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 180: 2)
      Correspondence and printed matter. Includes material on Austrian Lippizan horses
    - Human Life International, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 180: 3)
    - Institute of World Politics (Washington, D.C.), 1991-2001 (Box-folder 180: 4)
      Correspondence, speeches and grant proposals
    - International Theological Institute for Studies on Marriage and the Family (Gaming, Austria)
      Correspondence, memoranda, notes, minutes, statutes, financial records, meeting materials and printed matter. Clark was a member of the Board of Trustees
      - 1997 (Box-folder 180: 5)
      - 1998 (Box-folder 180: 6)
      - 1999 (Box-folder 181: 1-2, Box-folder 180: 7)
      - 2000 (Box-folder 182: 1, Box-folder 181: 3-4)
      - 2001 (Box-folder 182: 2-3)
      - 2002 (Box-folder 182: 4)
    - Ireland
      Correspondence, memoranda and printed matter. Includes material on the John Henry Newman Scholar Endowment Fund at University College, Dublin
      - 1989 (Box-folder 182: 5)
      - 1996-1997 (Box-folder 182: 6)
      - 1998-1999 (Box-folder 182: 7)
      - 2000-2002 (Box-folder 183: 1)
    - JU-87 Stuka airplanes, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 183: 2)
      Correspondence and printed matter, relating to a restoration project
    - Law
      Relates mainly to theory of natural law
      - General, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 183: 3)
        Correspondence, memoranda and speeches
      - Printed matter, 1985-1998 (Box-folder 183: 4)
    - Life Legal Defense Foundation, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 183: 5)
      Correspondence, memoranda, legal documents and printed matter
    - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1987 (Box-folder 183: 6)
      Correspondence, will and obituaries
    - Museum of Flying (Santa Monica, California)
      Correspondence, memoranda, meeting materials and printed matter. Clark was a member of the Board of Trustees
      - 1991-1993 (Box-folder 183: 7)
      - 1994 (Box-folder 184: 1)
      - 1995-2000 (Box-folder 184: 2)
    - National Council for Adoption (originally National Committee for Adoption)
      - Newsletters and financial report, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 184: 3)
      - Amicus curiae legal briefs, 1982-1997 (Box-folder 184: 4)
      - Pamphlets and reports, 1981-1997 (Box-folder 184: 5)
      - Adoption Factbook, 1989 (Box-folder 184: 6)
    - National Review, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 185: 1)
      Correspondence and miscellany. Mainly relates to Baltic cruise sponsored by the journal
    - Navaho and Hopi Indian relocation, 1985 (Box-folder 185: 2)
    - Nixon, Richard M., 1986 (Box-folder 185: 3)
      Memoranda and speeches by Nixon
    - Orocio (Juana Santos) Case
      Orocio was charged with abandonment of her newborn baby in Santa Maria, California. Clark became involved in the case as a friend of the court
      - General, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 185: 4)
        Correspondence, notes and miscellany
      - Legal documents, 2002 (Box-folder 185: 5)
      - Press coverage, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 185: 6)
    - Parents Rights Coalition, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 185: 7)
      Correspondence and bulletins
    - Parkway (Broadcasting service), 1985 (Box-folder 185: 8)
      Promotional material
    - President's Blue Ribbon Commission on Defense Management, 1986 (Box-folder 185: 9)
      Interim report. Clark was a member of the Commission
    - President's Blue Ribbon Task Group on Nuclear Weapons Program Management, 1985 (Box-folder 185: 10)
      Report, memoranda and clipping. Clark was chairman of the Task Group
    - Priests for Life, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 186: 1)
      Correspondence, newsletters and other issuances
    - Reagan (Ronald) and Reagan administration
      - Reagan administration official documents, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 186: 2)
        Memoranda, reports and speeches. Includes memorandum on ambassadorial selection and Federal Emergency Management Agency stockpile report
      - Casmir, Fred L., "Communication in Development Alternatives" (Department of State study), 1985 (Box-folder 186: 3)
      - Contemporary commentary, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 186: 4)
        Clippings, printed articles, pamphlet and miscellany
      - Retrospective commentary, 1990-2001 (Box-folder 186: 5)
        Clippings, printed articles and miscellany
      - Bailey, Norman A., The Strategic Plan That Won the Cold War, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 187: 1)
        Printed copy. Includes drafts of and working materials for a projected expanded version by Bailey and Roger W. Robinson, Jr., to be entitled "Winning the Cold War"
      - Lettow, Paul Vorbeck, "US President Ronald Reagan and the Strategic Defense Initiative,", 2003 (Box-folder 187: 2)
      - Reagan: A Life in Letters (edited by Kiron K. Skinner et al.)
        - General, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 187: 3)
          Correspondence, memorandum and printed article
        - Excerpts and endnotes (Box-folder 187: 4)
      - The Reagan Agenda (television documentary), 1996 (Box-folder 187: 5)
      - Reagan, in His Own Hand (edited by Kiron K. Skinner et al.), 2000-2001 (Box-folder 187: 6)
        Correspondence, memoranda and working materials
    - Religious Coalition on Moral Public Policy Issues, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 187: 7)
    - Right to life
      See also names of organizations involved with right to life issues
      - Correspondence, 1995-2000 (Box-folder 188: 1)
      - California Constitutional Amendment 38 (restricting abortion), 1996-1998 (Box-folder 188: 2)
        Text, correspondence and memoranda
      - American Academy of Pediatrics vs. Lungren (re abortion), 1995-1997 (Box-folder 188: 3)
        Legal briefs, correspondence and memoranda
      - Printed matter, 1991-2000 (Box-folder 188: 4-6)
    - Ronald Reagan Presidential Foundation
      Correspondence, memoranda, financial records, minutes, meeting materials and press coverage. Clark was a member of the Board of Trustees
      - 1985 (Box-folder 189: 1)
      - 1986 (Box-folder 189: 2)
      - 1987 (Box-folder 189: 3)
      - 1988 (Box-folder 189: 4-5)
    - South Africa, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 189: 6)
      Correspondence, memoranda, speeches and printed matter
    - Thomas Aquinas College (Santa Paula, California)
      - General
        - 1992-1994 (Box-folder 190: 1)
        - 1995 (Box-folder 190: 2)
        - 1996 (Box-folder 190: 3)
        - 1997-1999 (Box-folder 190: 4)
        - 2000-2002 (Box-folder 190: 5)
      - Newsletters, 1993-2002 (Box-folder 191: 1-2)
    - Timor-Leste (East Timor)
      Correspondence and printed matter, mainly relating to human rights issues. Includes some material on human rights elsewhere
      - 1999-2000 (Box-folder 191: 3)
      - 2001 (Box-folder 191: 4-5)
      - 2002 (Box-folder 191: 6)
    - United for Life, 1995 (Box-folder 192: 1)
    - United States Department of the Interior, 1985-1999 (Box-folder 192: 2)
    - Villanova Preparatory School (Ojai, California)
      Correspondence, financial records and printed matter
      - 1986-1987 (Box-folder 192: 3)
      - 1988-1989 (Box-folder 192: 4)
      - 1990 (Box-folder 192: 5)
      - 1991-1992 (Box-folder 192: 6)
      - 1993-1996 (Box-folder 192: 7)
      - 1997-2002 (Box-folder 192: 8)
    - Weinberger, Caspar, 2006 (Box-folder 192: 9)
      Obituaries and printed matter
    - World Association for Children and Parents, 1998 (Box-folder 192: 10)
      Promotional materials
    - Young America's Foundation
      Correspondence, memoranda, newsletters and printed matter. Clark was chairman of the Foundation's Reagan Ranch Board of Governors
      - 2000 (Box-folder 192: 11)
      - 2001-2004 (Box-folder 193: 1)
      - 2005-2008 (Box-folder 193: 2)
  - Printed matter, 1985-2001 (Box-folder 193: 3)
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 193: 4)
- Audiovisual File, circa 1930s-1990s
  Photographs, cartoons, audiotape cassettes and phonograph records
  - Pre-1981 photographs
    - Portraits of Clark as California Supreme Court justice (Box-folder 194: 1)
    - Clark and family (Box-folder 194: 2)
      Includes photograph of Clark as small boy with Shirley Temple
    - Clark with Ronald Reagan and members of the Reagan gubernatorial administration (Box-folder 194: 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 194: 4)
      Includes photograph of Mildred Lillie
  - 1981 photographs
    - Clark alone and with Alexander Haig (Box-folder 194: 5)
      Includes photographs of Clark's swearing-in ceremony as Deputy Secretary of State
    - Clark with Ronald Reagan and Cabinet (Box-folder 194: 6)
      Also includes John Gavin, Alexander Haig, Anwar Sadat, Dmitrii Shostakovich, Sylvester Stallone and Caspar Weinberger
    - Clark with other dignitaries (Box-folder 194: 7)
      Includes Richard V. Allen, Peter Dailey, John Gavin, Henry A. Kissinger, Tadhg O'Sullivan, Mstislav Rostropovich, Anwar Sadar, Dmitrii Shostakovich, Sylvester Stallone, Walter Stoessel and Caspar Weinberger
    - Clark on visit to South Africa (Box-folder 194: 8)
    - Visit to Southwest Africa (Namibia) (Box-folder 194: 9)
    - Clark on visit to Ireland (Box-folder 194: 10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 194: 11)
  - 1982 photographs
    - Clark with Ronald Reagan and Cabinet (Box-folder 195: 1-2)
      Also includes James Baker, John R. Block, George Bush, William J. Casey, Michael Deaver, Gerald Ford, Indira Gandhi, Alexander Haig, Jeane Kirkpatrick, Helmut Kohl, Robert McFarlane, Edwin Meese, Francois Mitterrand, Paul Nitze, George P. Shultz, Walter Stoessel and Caspar Weinberger
    - Clark with other dignitaries (Box-folder 195: 3)
      Includes Alexander Haig, Pope John Paul II, Clare Boothe Luce, Hosni Mubarak, Eugene V. Rostow, George P. Shultz, Helmut Schmidt and Caspar Weinberger
    - Clark Land Company property (Box-folder 195: 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 195: 5)
  - 1983 photographs
    - Clark with Ronald Reagan and Cabinet (Box-folder 195: 6-7)
      Also includes James Baker, George Bush, Jeane Kirkpatrick, Helmut Kohl, Edwin Meese, Donald Regan, Qaboos bin Said, George P. Shultz, Margaret Thatcher, Pierre Trudeau and Helene Von Damm, and Williamsburg Economic Summit meeting
    - Clark with other dignitaries (Box-folder 196: 1-2)
      Includes George Bush, Nicholas Salgo, Lewis Tambs, Pierre Trudeau and Helene Von Damm, and National Security Council farewell celebration for Clark
    - Portraits of Clark as Secretary of the Interior (Box-folder 196: 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 196: 4)
  - 1984 photographs
    - Clark with Ronald Reagan (Box-folder 196: 5)
      Also includes Pope John Paul II
    - U.S. Geological Survey National Center anniversary celebration (Box-folder 196: 6)
    - Garrison Diversion Unit Commission hearings (Box-folder 196: 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 196: 8)
  - Undated (1981-1984) photographs
    - Clark portraits (Box-folder 197: 1)
    - Portraits of Joan Clark (wife of William P. Clark) (Box-folder 197: 2)
    - Clark with Ronald Reagan and Cabinet (Box-folder 197: 3)
      Also includes Michael Deaver, Alexander Haig, Jeane Kirkpatrick, Edwin Meese, George P. Shultz and Caspar Weinberger
    - Clark with other dignitaries (Box-folder 197: 4)
      Includes Shirley Temple Black, George Bush, Alexander Haig, Saddam Hussein and Helene Von Damm
  - Post-1984 photographs
    - Clark and others (Box-folder 197: 5)
      Includes George Bush, Clare Boothe Luce and William E. Simon, Jr.
    - Unidentified scenes in Southeast Asia (Box-folder 197: 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 197: 7)
      Includes scenes of Gherini Ranch, Thomas Aquinas College and Villanova Preparatory School
  - Cartoons of Clark as Secretary of the Interior, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 197: 8)
  - Oversize photographs, circa 1981-1984 (Box-folder 198: 1)
    Include Clark with Jeane Kirkpatrick, Ronald Reagan and Helene Von Damm
  - Album of photographs of Clark's commencement address delivery, Pepperdine University, 1983 (Box-folder 198: 2)
  - Album of photographs of Clark horseback-riding at Rock Creek Park, District of Columbia, 1984 (Box-folder 198: 3)
  - Audiotape cassettes (Cassette cabinet)
    Includes recording of Clark's address to the Texas and Southwestern Cattle Raisers Association, 1985
  - Sound disc of songs in conjunction with Western Olympics, 1984 (Record cabinet)